Hello English learners and welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
How are you, Erica?
你好吗，Erica？
Marco, I'm doing really well today.
Marco，我今天感觉非常好。
You excited?
你兴奋吗？
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
We've got a great lesson for everyone.
我们为大家准备了一堂很棒的课。
Yes, we have a really common situation where we're going to use real English, right?
是的，我们有一个非常常见的情景，会用到真实英语，对吧？
Yep, everyday English, English that people really use.
对，日常英语，人们真正使用的英语。
And that's what we want you to learn.
这就是我们希望你们学的。
What are we talking about today specifically?
今天我们具体要谈什么？
Today we have a really common situation that is a little bit embarrassing.
今天我们有一个非常常见的情景，有点尴尬。
All right, an embarrassing situation.
好吧，一个尴尬的情景。
So let's listen to the dialogue for the first time and it's going to be kind of fast.
那我们第一次听对话，语速会有点快。
Yeah, but don't worry if you don't understand everything because after 10 minutes you'll
是的，但如果没全听懂也别担心，因为十分钟后你
understand everything.
就全懂了。
Perfect.
完美。
All right, let's listen.
好了，我们来听吧。
Nick, how's it going?
Nick，最近怎么样？
Oh, hey.
哦，嘿。
What are you doing in this neighborhood?
你在这个街区做什么？
Do you live around here?
你住这附近吗？
Actually, my office is right around the corner.
其实，我的办公室就在拐角处。
It was great to meet you last week at the conference.
上周在会议上见到你真是太好了。
I really enjoyed our conversation about foreign investment.
我真的很享受我们关于外国投资的谈话。
Yeah, yeah, it was really interesting.
是啊，是啊，真的很有趣。
You know, I'm in a bit of a hurry, but here's my card.
你知道，我有点赶时间，但这是我的名片。
We should definitely meet up again and continue our discussion.
我们一定要再见面，继续我们的讨论。
Sure, you still have my contact details, right?
当然，你还有我的联系方式，对吧？
You know what?
你知道吗？
This is really embarrassing, but your name has just slipped my mind.
这真的很尴尬，但我一时想不起你的名字了。
Can you remind me?
你能提醒我一下吗？
Sure.
当然。
My name is Anna Farris.
我叫Anna Farris。
Don't worry about it.
别在意。
It happens to me all the time.
这种事我经常遇到。
I'm terrible with names too.
我也不擅长记名字。
Wow, Nick forgot her name.
哇，Nick忘了她的名字。
Yeah, that's happened to me a couple of times, and I'm going to tell you about it a little
是啊，这种事我也遇到过几次，我待会会跟你们说说。
bit later.
稍晚一点。
Okay.
好的。
All right, well, let's start with our three language takeaways.
好了，那我们开始今天的三个语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So our first word on our language takeaway is in a bit of a hurry.
第一个语言要点是“有点匆忙”。
In a bit of a hurry.
有点匆忙。
So Nick was in a hurry.
所以尼克当时很匆忙。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
This is a great phrase.
这个短语很棒。
So let's listen to three examples of how you can use this phrase.
我们来听三个例子，看看怎么用这个短语。
Example one.
例子一。
Can you drive faster?
你能开快点吗？
I'm in a bit of a hurry.
我有点赶时间。
Example two.
例子二。
I can't talk right now.
我现在没法说话。
I'm in a bit of a hurry.
我有点赶时间。
Example three.
例子三。
I'm in a bit of a hurry, so I'll check these files later.
我有点赶时间，所以这些文件我晚点再看。
Okay, so it's clear now.
好了，现在清楚了。
Basically it means that you don't have time.
基本上就是说你没时间。
You're moving really quickly.
你动作很快。
Okay, perfect.
好的，完美。
Now let's look at our second language takeaway word, and it's contact details.
现在来看第二个语言要点，是“联系方式”。
Contact details.
联系方式。
So what are your contact details?
那你的联系方式是什么？
Basically, this is the information you can find on your business card.
基本上，就是你在名片上能找到的信息。
All right, so we have like our name, our telephone number.
好的，比如我们的姓名、电话号码。
Your email address, perhaps your mobile phone number.
你的电子邮件地址，也许还有手机号码。
So all the useful information so people can get in touch with you.
所有有用的信息，方便别人联系你。
Yeah, so people can phone you or email you.
是的，这样别人可以给你打电话或发邮件。
Okay, so contact details.
好的，联系方式。
Great.
很好。
Okay, so our third word is slipped my mind.
好的，第三个词是“忘了”。
Slipped my mind.
忘了。
So this is a funny phrase.
这个短语很有趣。
It's kind of strange, right?
有点奇怪，对吧？
Yeah, slipped my mind.
是啊，我忘了。
It sounds very weird.
听起来很奇怪。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, so now we're going to listen to two examples of this phrase.
好了，现在我们来听两个这个短语的例子。
Try and see if you can figure out what it means.
试着看看你能不能猜出它的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm sorry I forgot to respond to your email.
抱歉我忘了回复你的邮件。
Just slipped my mind.
就是忘了。
Example two.
例子二。
Don't you know what day it is today?
你不知道今天是什么日子吗？
Oh, it's your birthday.
哦，是你生日。
It completely slipped my mind.
我完全忘了。
Ah, so slipped my mind is like I forgot.
啊，所以 slipped my mind 就像是我忘了。
You forgot something.
你忘了某事。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
So, accidentally.
所以是不小心。
Right.
对。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
Now it's time for putting it together.
现在是“组合运用”环节。
Putting it together.
组合运用。
All right, Erika, why don't you tell our listeners what putting it together is?
好的，Erika，你为什么不告诉我们的听众“组合运用”是什么呢？
Well, putting it together helps you put language together.
嗯，“组合运用”帮助你组合语言。
It helps you be more fluent by knowing how words fit together.
它通过让你了解单词如何搭配，帮助你更流利。
Great.
很好。
So let's look at our first phrase today.
那我们来看看今天的第一个短语。
And it's around here.
就是 around here。
Around here.
Around here。
So this is like close by.
这就像是在附近。
Close by.
在附近。
We can say, for example, is there a bank around here?
比如我们可以说，这附近有银行吗？
Yeah, yeah.
对，对。
So that's, is there a bank close to here?
所以就是，这附近有银行吗？
Exactly.
没错。
Now, this phrase, around here, we can change it a little bit and it means something a little
现在，这个短语 around here，我们可以稍微改一下，意思会有点不同。
bit different.
对。
Right.
I could say, Marco, there's a great restaurant right around the corner.
我可以说，Marco，拐角处就有一家很棒的餐厅。
Right.
对。
And that would mean there is a great restaurant on the other street.
那就意味着另一条街上有一家很棒的餐厅。
Yep.
嗯。
Around the corner.
在拐角处。
Yep.
嗯。
Great.
很好。
And another example, we can say around there.
再举个例子，我们可以说“around there”。
Around there.
在那附近。
Right.
对。
So, for example, I can say, Los Angeles is a great city.
比如，我可以说，洛杉矶是个很棒的城市。
I used to live around there.
我以前住在那附近。
So you used to live near Los Angeles.
所以你以前住在洛杉矶附近。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
It's a really good phrase and it's really common.
这个短语很好，也很常用。
Yeah.
是的。
Now, our next phrase in putting it together is terrible with.
现在，我们下一个要组合的短语是“terrible with”。
Terrible with.
不擅长。
And I have a couple of examples that will show you how this phrase works.
我有几个例子可以展示这个短语的用法。
Example one.
例子一。
You're terrible with numbers.
你不擅长数字。
You can't even remember your own telephone number.
你连自己的电话号码都记不住。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm terrible with directions.
我不擅长认路。
I'm always getting lost.
我总是迷路。
Example three.
例子三。
I'm terrible with faces.
我不擅长记人脸。
I can never remember what people look like.
我总记不住别人长什么样。
Wow.
哇。
I understand that.
我理解。
I'm also terrible with numbers.
我也不擅长数字。
I can barely add two plus two.
我连二加二都算不好。
Well, yeah, I guess not everyone is a numbers person.
嗯，是啊，我想不是每个人都擅长数字。
I'm terrible with faces.
我不擅长记人脸。
I sometimes forget what people look like.
我有时会忘记别人长什么样。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Uh-oh.
哦哦。
I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue a second time.
我觉得是时候再听一遍我们的对话了。
OK, this time the dialogue will be a little bit slower.
好的，这次对话会稍微慢一点。
Right.
没错。
So try and listen for some of the words we've just talked about.
所以试着听出我们刚才讨论的一些单词。
Nick, how's it going?
尼克，最近怎么样？
Oh, hey.
哦，嘿。
What are you doing in this neighborhood?
你在这个街区做什么？
Do you live around here?
你住在这附近吗？
Actually, my office is right around the corner.
其实，我的办公室就在拐角处。
It was great to meet you last week at the conference.
上周在会议上见到你真是太好了。
I really enjoyed our conversation about foreign investment.
我真的很喜欢我们关于外国投资的谈话。
Yeah, yeah, it was really interesting.
是啊，是啊，真的很有趣。
You know, I'm in a bit of a hurry, but here's my card.
你知道，我有点赶时间，但这是我的名片。
We should definitely meet up again and continue our discussion.
我们一定要再见面，继续我们的讨论。
Sure.
当然。
You still have my contact details, right?
你还有我的联系方式，对吧？
You know what?
你知道吗？
This is really embarrassing, but your name has just slipped my mind.
这真的很尴尬，但我一时想不起你的名字了。
Can you remind me?
你能提醒我一下吗？
Sure.
当然。
My name is Anna Faris.
我叫安娜·法瑞丝。
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
It happens to me all the time.
这种事我经常遇到。
I'm terrible with names too.
我也不擅长记名字。
So it's more clear now.
所以现在更清楚了吧。
You can understand a lot better, right?
你能理解得更好，对吧？
Yeah, that's true.
是的，没错。
Great.
太好了。
Now, it's time for us to take a look at Fluency Builder.
现在，我们来看看流利度构建器。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
So with Fluency Builder, we take some very simple phrases and show you how you can be
通过流利度构建器，我们选取一些非常简单的短语，并向你展示如何能
more fluent or how you can...
更流利，或者如何能……
Sound more native.
听起来更地道。
Yeah.
是的。
Great.
太好了。
In the beginning of the dialogue, Anna said, Nick, how's it going?
在对话开头，安娜说：“尼克，最近怎么样？”
Yeah, this is a great phrase.
是的，这是一个很棒的短语。
It sounds really, really natural.
听起来非常非常自然。
You know, sometimes I hear students say, how are you?
你知道，有时我听到学生说“你好吗？”
Or, how are you doing?
或者“你怎么样？”
Those are two great phrases, but this one sounds really, really natural.
这两个短语都很棒，但这个听起来非常非常自然。
It just sounds more casual.
它听起来更随意。
Yeah, let's listen again to that phrase from the dialogue.
是的，我们再听一遍对话中的那个短语。
How's it going?
最近怎么样？
Great.
很好。
So next time that you find a friend on the street, you can just say, hey, how's it going?
所以下次你在街上遇到朋友时，可以直接说，嘿，最近怎么样？
Yeah.
是的。
So Marco, have you ever forgotten someone's name?
那么马可，你有没有忘记过别人的名字？
Yeah, it's happened to me a couple of times.
有，我遇到过几次。
And actually, the most embarrassing situation was that I forgot a family member's name.
实际上，最尴尬的一次是我忘记了一个家人的名字。
No, a family member's name.
不会吧，家人的名字。
We had like a family reunion and there were a lot of aunts and uncles and cousins that
我们当时有个家庭聚会，有很多叔叔、阿姨和堂兄弟姐妹，
I hadn't seen in a while.
我很久没见他们了。
And I just forgot one of my uncle's names.
然后我就忘记了我一个叔叔的名字。
And I was...
我当时……
Uh-oh, that's pretty embarrassing.
哎呀，那太尴尬了。
Yeah.
是啊。
So what did you do?
那你怎么办了？
Well, I had to ask one of my other cousins.
嗯，我不得不问我的一个堂兄弟。
I'm like, hey, who is that guy?
我说，嘿，那个人是谁？
He's like, oh, that's Uncle John.
他说，哦，那是约翰叔叔。
I'm like, oh man, I totally forgot.
我说，哦天哪，我完全忘了。
Yeah.
是啊。
So it was really embarrassing because I didn't know what to call him.
所以真的很尴尬，因为我不知道该怎么称呼他。
So I just called him Uncle because I didn't know his name.
所以我只好叫他叔叔，因为我不知道他的名字。
Hi, Uncle.
嗨，叔叔。
Yeah.
是啊。
Oh, yeah.
哦，对。
So when that happens to me, when I'm in a business setting, sometimes what I do is I
所以当我遇到这种情况时，如果是在商务场合，我有时会
ask for someone's card.
问别人要名片。
Yeah, that's the good technique.
嗯，这是个好办法。
Yeah.
是的。
Or sometimes I might ask them to write down their email because usually their full name
或者有时我会让他们写下邮箱，因为通常他们的全名
is spelled in their email address.
会拼写在邮箱地址里。
So that's my trick when I've forgotten someone's name.
这就是我忘记别人名字时的小窍门。
That's a good trick.
好主意。
And I guess a lot of our listeners can take your advice on that.
我想很多听众可以采纳你的建议。
Okay.
好的。
So I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue one more time, this time at natural
所以我想是时候再听一遍我们的对话了，这次是正常语速。
speed.
速度。
Nick, how's it going?
尼克，最近怎么样？
Oh, hey.
哦，嘿。
What are you doing in this neighborhood?
你在这个街区做什么？
Do you live around here?
你住在这附近吗？
Actually, my office is right around the corner.
其实，我的办公室就在拐角处。
It was great to meet you last week at the conference.
上周在会议上见到你真是太好了。
I really enjoyed our conversation about foreign investment.
我真的很喜欢我们关于外国投资的讨论。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
It was really interesting.
真的很有趣。
You know, I'm in a bit of a hurry, but here's my card.
你知道，我有点赶时间，但这是我的名片。
We should definitely meet up again and continue our discussion.
我们一定要再见面，继续我们的讨论。
Sure.
当然。
You still have my contact details, right?
你还有我的联系方式，对吧？
You know what?
你知道吗？
This is really embarrassing, but your name has just slipped my mind.
这真的很尴尬，但我一时想不起你的名字了。
Can you remind me?
你能提醒我一下吗？
Sure.
当然。
My name is Anna Farris.
我叫安娜·法里斯。
Don't worry about it.
别担心。
You say this to me all the time.
你总是这样对我说。
I'm terrible with names too.
我也不擅长记名字。
Well, I hope that you've all enjoyed our lesson for today, and remember to check out
好了，希望你们喜欢今天的课程，记得去查看
our website at EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Where you can find a lot of other resources and you can leave all your questions and comments.
在那里你可以找到很多其他资源，也可以留下你的问题和评论。
Yeah.
是的。
Marco and I are always on the site, so we're happy to answer all of your questions.
马可和我经常在网站上，所以我们很乐意回答你们的所有问题。
Exactly.
没错。
So now it's time for us to say...
所以现在是时候说……
Goodbye.
再见。